it is 4:00 in the morning and I'm awake
due to fire alarm malfunction and it's
now solved but Emily it's been two
nights in a row but it is 5:00 and I've
been awake for over an hour and in less
than an hour I have a conversation
booked to somebody with their own
world-saving
idea I'm looking forward to that but I
was hoping to wake up 15 minutes
beforehand not two hours beforehand and
so sitting here with a piece of paper
looking to facilitate a solution raising
on my own
possibly just because every two weeks
isn't often enough for me so just
working through it staying for food
what's working what's not working with
the idea what it could look like and
then what we could do with 10,000 people
and $100,000 and well I was writing it
out the difference between it this
difference do the micro and the macro
that what we're dealing with in solution
raising is like what's working and not
working on scale right so climate change
is something that's not working on scale
because we're all getting the effects
and some people way more effects than
others on that level but the truth is
that we can't actually deal with things
on the macro level we can only deal with
them on the micro level so an economics
micro level is individual choices and a
business's choices and the macro is
basically government and country's
choices so it's like top-down versus
bottom-up economics and although my
brain and my conscience deal with the
macro level I care about the
interconnectedness of the planet and
people we don't actually affect things
on that scale it has to hit somebody on
the micro scale so if you don't care
about the environment the environment
it's not gonna be a way that you shop
right
you don't care about the direct impact
your purchases have on other human
beings other the animals or the systems
as a whole then having that information
isn't gonna help you
but anyway so changing the questions
from like what is working for us to what
is working for you what is it working
for us to what is it working for you
right what in your life how you're
eating if you were dealing a food or how
you're getting your health care what
does that look like to you what's
working for you what's not working for
you and then what would your ideal
situation look like in that that one is
someone extrapolating what would work
for you two what would work for everyone
what could a perfect system look like
like the problem is is when people need
when people only deal with the micro
level like the system can only change at
the micro level my brain works at the
macro level and the micro level but the
macro level is where like that is where
utopian ideals want to like settle is on
the macro but all it can do is impact
the micro just like if and this is like
I get this on a different level before
that we can't change we can't write laws
we can't decide on new taxation policy
doing any of that stuff is very arduous
what we can do is come up with new
systems that help people on the micro
level have a better impacted macro level
so if we want the masses to eat in an
environmentally friendly way we can't
actually design it for the masses and I
already knew that we have to design it
for the individual it has to be the
individual who comes and says it needs
to be cheap it needs to be convenient it
needs to be within my ethics and values
instead of here the ethics and values
here's you must eat under this like how
can we actually help you reach your goal
and
meet the mackerel goals on a bigger
level and the system whatever solution
we focus on has to be something that is
a natural attractor to at least the
people who created it
but hopefully beyond hopefully you are
dealing with the 90% what makes the 90%
not the fringe 10% that cares deeply
about the environmental cost to the nth
degree or the human cost the nth degree
but because I think every like so my
hypothesis is wrong that everyone does
care it's just too overwhelming to care
that if given the choice between slavery
and non slavery 99% of individuals would
choose non slavery and yet 99% of us
choose slavery because it's too
overwhelming like where do I get a
computer it's not dependent on slavery I
have to not use a computer it doesn't
work right so like those two things
don't actually go together her brains
hurt our hearts hurt and I was older but
anyway up at 4 I am thinking about the
difference between the micro and the
macro